(
"ai_sub_version": "2.9.1",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 7,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 15,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.1-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true
),
"gemini_cli": (
"timeout": 600,
"overwrite_system_prompt": false
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch"
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"run": 5,
"max": 5,
"delay": 30
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false
)
Tokoyami Towa 6th Anniversary LIVE
常闇トワ 6周年記念 LIVE Rock festa!!!
Tokoyami Towa 6th Anniversary LIVE Rock festa!!!
Artist
常闇トワ
Tokoyami Towa
Guest
鷹嶺ルイ
Takane Lui
輪堂千速
Rindo Chihaya
IRyS
音乃瀬奏
Otonose Kanade
AZKi
夏色まつり
Natsuiro Matsuri
森カリオペ
Mori Calliope
猫汰つな
Nekota Tsuna
Ah 呆れだす空に
Ah, beneath the exasperating sky,
差し替えられた幻想に架かった固定概念と
hung over a swapped-out illusion and fixed concepts,
浅はかじみた答えじゃ
with such shallow answers,
見透かされてしまうな
I'll be seen right through.
この道を渡りきっても
Even if I cross this road,
まだ視界は曇っている
my vision is still cloudy.
履き違えた大人になってから
Ever since I became a misguided adult,
縮みきった歩幅と感情
my stride and emotions have shrunk completely.
削りだした身体に対して気づけと歌っている
I sing to my worn-down body, urging it to notice.
はみ出した心じゃいられないのならさ
If I can't live with an overflowing heart,
染みついたこの青さを切り離してしまっていい
then I can just cut away this deeply-stained youth.
ずっと語りかけてた日々を
The days I kept talking to,
嘆くように
as if in lament...
深い闇に呑み込まれないよって
Saying, "Don't get swallowed by the deep darkness."
詰まりきった現実に答えなんてない
There are no answers in this choked reality.
逃げ出してしまった言葉を羽織って
Wearing the words that have run away,
溶けだした心を胸に隠している
I hide my melting heart inside my chest.
冷えきってしまった身体を騙すように
As if to deceive my frozen body,
描きかけた何時かも枯れた夢を
the half-drawn dream that has long since withered,
なぞっている
I am tracing it.
Ah 暴れだす言葉に
Ah, with words starting to rampage,
差し替えられた幻想に架かった固定概念と
hung over a swapped-out illusion and fixed concepts,
立ち止まりそうじゃ
if I look like I'm about to stop,
見透かされてしまうな
I'll be seen right through.
この道を渡りきっても
Even if I cross this road,
また誓いだ、続いていく
it's another vow that keeps on going.
履き違えた大人になってから
Ever since I became a misguided adult,
浮かびだした思いの回想
recalling the thoughts that bubbled up,
ずっと見えなくなった足跡を探している
I've been searching for footprints that disappeared long ago.
はみ出した心じゃいられないのならさ
If I can't live with an overflowing heart,
染みきったこの青さをさらけ出してしまっていい
then I can just expose this deeply-permeated blue.
ずっと語りかけてた日々を
The days I kept talking to,
隠すように
as if to hide them...
深い闇に呑み込まれないよって
Saying, "Don't get swallowed by the deep darkness."
決まりきった現実に答えなんていらない
I don't need any answers in this fixed reality.
逃げ出してしまった言葉を羽織って
Wearing the words that have run away,
溶けだした心を胸に隠している
I hide my melting heart inside my chest.
冷えきってしまった身体を騙すように
As if to deceive my frozen body,
描きかけた何時かも枯れた夢を
the half-drawn dream that has long since withered,
なぞって
tracing it...
Ah 錆びついている今をただ
Ah, this rusted present, I just...
不安定に立つ
stand unstably.
裏返る脳裏に寄せられてしまった
Brought to the back of my mind,
あの人達に向かっては留まっていた
facing those people, it lingered,
手放してしまったのに
even though I've let them go...
逃げ出してしまった言葉を羽織って
Wearing the words that have run away,
溶けだした心を胸に隠している
I hide my melting heart inside my chest.
冷えきってしまった身体を騙すように
As if to deceive my frozen body,
描きかけた何時かも枯れた夢を
the half-drawn dream that has long since withered,
なぞっている
I am tracing it.
Can you hear me when I cry in desperation?
Nothing comes along with my expectation
How much pain and ache you’re feeling?
Breathing?
I gotta change this situation
アダルトスーツ
Adult Suit
アダルトなキグルミ着てる僕
I'm wearing an adult costume
心はいつも不安定 天秤シーソー
My heart is always unstable, like a seesaw
まさかの発言で凍り付かす
An unexpected remark freezes everything
色見え隠れ
My true colors peek out
血迷うボク
Losing my mind
今日の今この瞬間に放とうとする
The words I try to speak
言葉がいつも後ろ髪引く
at this very moment always pull me back
全部ダメダメ なんてでしょ？ じゃあもう放棄して！
Everything is no good, right? Then just give it up!
ハナから無かった事にしよ！！
Let's pretend it never happened from the start!!
ラリるラリラリラ
Rari ru rari rari ra
それじゃダメダメ 悪いクセだね！ もうしない！
That's no good, that's a bad habit! I won't do it anymore!
どうせ着せられているならキメキメでいこう！
If I'm being forced to wear it, let's dress to kill!
何もかもが暗く黒く見える！
Everything looks dark and black!
色メガネ付きの
Through tinted glasses
アダルトなパチモンスーツ
wearing an adult knock-off suit
必殺技×0で全部消し去ろうか？ 強気なボク
Should I erase it all with special move x 0? Confident me
だけど実際はやっぱり出来やしないの
But in reality, I can't do it after all
身軽さを奪われ動けない
Stripped of my agility, I can't move
それでうまいことバランスとれてるんだよ！
That's how we keep a good balance!
きみは耳元でそれを言う！
You whisper that in my ear!
それにしちゃ少しあんまりじゃない？
But isn't that a little too much?
っていうか不公平じゃない？
Or rather, isn't it unfair?
どうせ勝ち目なんてないし
Since there's no chance of winning anyway,
食い気味でいこう！
let's jump right into it!
I feel this moment
No one can take it
そう 何回だって 伝わらなけりゃ 意味無い！
Yeah, no matter how many times, if it doesn't get through, it's meaningless!
今日の今この瞬間が大事なの！
This moment, right now, is what matters!
奪う権利はあなた方にはない！！
You have no right to take it away!!
全部ダメダメ！ 何がダメダメ？ なんでしょう？
Everything is no good! What's no good? Tell me!
納得いくまで話してよ！
Talk to me until I'm satisfied!
どうせ屁理屈並べるんだろ？ バカみたい
You'll just make excuses anyway, it's pathetic
とどめをさす気でいるなら？
If you intend to finish me off,
今がチャンスだぞ！
now is your chance!
はーい！ということで、常闇トワ6周年記念LIVEにお越しいただきありがとうございます！
Hi! So, thank you so much for coming to the Tokoyami Towa 6th Anniversary Live!
はい！ということで、なんと本日6周年を迎えました！イェーイ！
Yes! And so, we have reached our 6th anniversary today! Yay!
ろ、ろく？ 悪魔の数字「6」？
S-Six? The devil's number '6'?
ということは今年はトワちゃんの年ということでいいでしょうか？ま、良くないか。いいか！
So, is it safe to say this is Towa-chan's year? Well, maybe not... It's fine!
ま、人によってはトワちゃんの、ね、あの、年にしちゃっていいということで！
Well, for some of you, you can make it Towa-chan's year!
はい、よろしくお願いします。ということで本日のハッシュ...
Yes, I appreciate your support. So, today's hash...
届いたかな？
Did it reach you?
てれれれれん！
Da-da-da-da-dum!
常闇トワ 6周年記念LIVE！よろしくお願いします！
This is the Tokoyami Towa 6th Anniversary Live! Please look forward to it!
目指せトレンド入り！
Let's aim to get trending!
えー、そしてね、この後はね、いろんな告知もありますので、最後まで見ていってくれればなと思います！
And after this, we have various announcements, so I hope you watch until the very end!
はい、えー、で今日なんですけれども、えー1月3日となっておりまして、
Yes! As for today, it is January 3rd,
えー世の中はお休みの日ということで、えー私もお休みの日ということで、
and since it's a holiday for everyone, and a holiday for me as well,
本日のライブは全編収録となっております。よろしくお願いいたします。
today's live is fully pre-recorded. Thank you for understanding!
そして、この後はなんとゲストパート！
And up next is the guest part!
いっぱい、いろんなね、ゲストが出てくれるので、楽しみに見ていってくれればなと思います！
Lots of different guests will be appearing, so please look forward to it!
では！ゲストパート、どうぞ！
Now, let's start the guest part!
絆ノ奇跡 / 作詞・作曲：Jean-Ken Johnny
[Song: Kizuna no Kiseki / Lyrics/Composition: Jean-Ken Johnny]
闇夜を駆け抜けて 何処へむかう
Racing through the dark night, where are we heading?
月明かりだけがただ一つの道標
Only the moonlight is our only guidepost
痛みも悲しみも拭いきれず
Unable to wipe away the pain and sadness
されどこの胸 of 炎は消させない
Yet, I won't let the flame in this chest be extinguished
誰が為に僕たちは この想いを貫いて
For whose sake are we carrying through with these feelings?
闇を裂き 陽の下で 光さす日まで
Tear through the darkness, under the sun, until the day the light shines
解き放たれた心に宿した火よ
Oh, the fire that dwells in the unleashed heart
舞い上げ、まとえ 今 夜明けの向こう側へ
Soar, wear it now, to the other side of the dawn
君がいる この世界もう一度愛せるまで
Until I can love the world you exist in once more
我が命 果てようとも 繋いで行こう
Even if my life meets its end, let us continue to connect
絆が紡いで 生まれた奇跡を
The miracle born from the thread of bonds
昨日の哀楽 夢揺らめいてる現世
The joys and sorrows of yesterday, the transient world where dreams sway
互いの正義をまた繰り返し振りかざす
Once again, repeatedly brandishing our own justice
誰が為に繋ぐ命
For whose sake do we connect our lives?
交わり縺れる定め
Intersecting, tangling destinies
邪の道 溢たの罪 すべて薙ぎ払え
The wicked path, countless sins, sweep them all away!
解き放て今 僕らが起こした火を
Unleash now, the fire we kindled!
舞い上げ 走れば 明日が変わるはず
Soar, and if we run, tomorrow should change
君といる この世界 二度と放さずに
Being with you, never letting go of this world again
君と共にいく
I will go together with you
瞼を閉じても 思い出すあの日を
Even if I close my eyes, I remember that day
打ちのめされても 焦がれた未来を
Even if we are beaten down, I still yearn for that future
いつの日か君に 捧げて見せよう
One day, I will show you that I can dedicate it to you
解き放たれた心に宿した火よ
Oh, the fire that dwells in the unleashed heart
舞い上げ、まとえ 今 夜明けの向こうへ
Soar, wear it now, to the other side of the dawn
解き放て今 僕らが起こした火を
Unleash now, the fire we kindled!
舞い上げ 走れば 明日が変わるはず
Soar, and if we run, tomorrow should change
君がいた この世界 もう一度愛せるまで
Until I can love this world you were in once more
我が命 果てようとも 繋げて行くよ
Even if my life meets its end, I will keep connecting
絆が紡いで 生まれた奇跡を
The miracle born from the thread of bonds...
抱きしめられた記憶から流れ出てた赤い雫
Red droplets flowing out from the memories of being held tight,
人様に見せるもんじゃないの
they're not something to be shown to others.
伝えなかった言葉たちがもう一人の私になって
The words I left unsaid became another me,
体の内側で何かを叫んでる
screaming something deep inside my body.
欲しかったのに 悔しかったのに
Even though I wanted it, even though it was frustrating...
駄目だよ 全部隠しておくの
No, I have to keep it all hidden.
ごめんね
I'm sorry.
悲しいのは私一人で十分だからと
Saying that being sad is enough with just me alone,
これ以上醜くなりたくないのと
saying that I don't want to become any uglier than this.
私の中で誰にも見つけられずに
Inside of me, without being found by anyone,
こんな色になるまで泣いていたんだね
you were crying until you turned this color.
綺麗だよ
It's beautiful.
渡しそびれた心から流れ出た青い雫
Blue droplets flowing out from the heart I failed to hand over,
人様に見せるもんじゃないの
they're not something to be shown to others.
何度も深く深く深く潜って 遠くの海の底に沈んで
Diving deep, deep, deep down over and over, sinking to the bottom of a distant sea,
そのまま宝石にでもなれるのを待つの
waiting to eventually turn into a gemstone just like that.
本当は嘘で飾って
To tell the truth, decorating it with lies,
ぬくもりみたいな優しさで慰めて
comforting myself with a warmth-like kindness.
誰かの悲劇で自分の悲劇を癒やして
Healing my own tragedy with someone else's tragedy,
恋しさに溺れた瞬間のままで
remaining in the exact moment of drowning in longing,
息もできずただ愛しているの
unable to even breathe, I'm just in love.
悲しいのは私一人で十分だからと
Saying that being sad is enough with just me alone,
これ以上醜くなりたくないのと
saying that I don't want to become any uglier than this.
私の中で誰にも見つけられずに
Inside of me, without being found by anyone,
こんな色になるまで泣いていたんだね
you were crying until you turned this color.
綺麗だよ
It's beautiful.
ごめんね
I'm sorry.
綺麗だよ
It's beautiful.
片っぽで丸を作って しっかり持ってて
Make a loop with one side, and hold it tight.
もう片っぽでその丸の後ろを ぐるっと回って
Take the other side, wrap it around the back of the loop.
間にできたポッケに入って 出て来るの待ってて
Slip it into the pocket made in between, and wait for it to come out.
出てきたところを迎えにきて 「せーの」で引っ張って
Go meet the part that comes out, and pull together on "one, two, three!"
はじめはなんとも 情けない形だとしても
Even if it looks terribly pathetic at first,
同じだけ力を込めて
put the same amount of strength into both sides.
羽根は大きく 結び目は固く
I want the wings to be large, and the knot to be tight,
なるようにきつく 結んでいてほしいの
I want you to tie it firmly so it becomes like that.
手はここに
Keep your hands here,
思い出は遠くに
and leave the memories far behind,
置いておいてほしいの
that's how I want you to keep it.
蝶々結び
[Song: Butterfly Knot]
片っぽでも引っ張っちゃえばほどけちゃうけど
If you pull on just one end, it will unravel, but...
作ったもの壊すのは遙かに簡単だけど
destroying what was made is far easier, though.
だけど解く時も そう ちゃんと
But when you undo it, yes, properly...
結んだ時と同じようにね
do it just like when we tied it, okay?
分かってるよ でもできたらね
I know, but if we can...
せーので引っ張って
let's pull on three!
ほどけやしないようにと願って力込めては
Hoping it won't come undone, as we put our strength into it...
広げすぎた羽に
with these wings spread too wide...
戸惑う
we feel lost.
羽は大きく 結び目は固く
Hoping the wings are large and the knot is tight,
なるようにきつく結んでいてほしいの
I want you to tie it firmly so it stays that way.
夢はここに
May the dreams be here,
想いは遠くに
may the feelings reach far away,
気付けばそこにあるくらいがいい
and it's best if we just happen to find it right there.
黙って引っ張ったりしないでよ
Don't go pulling it without warning.
不格好な蝶にしないでよ
Don't turn it into a clumsy butterfly.
結んだつもりがほどけていたり
Thinking we tied it, but it has unravelled,
緩めたつもりが締めていたり
thinking we loosened it, but it has tightened.
この蒼くて広い世界に
In this blue, vast world,
無数に散らばった中から
from among countless scattered threads,
別々に二人選んだ糸を
the threads that the two of us chose separately,
お互いたぐり寄せ合ったんだ
we pulled them together towards each other.
結ばれたんじゃなく結んだんだ
It wasn't tied for us; we tied it ourselves.
二人でせーので引っ張ったんだ
The two of us pulled it on three!
大きくも小さくもなりすぎないように
So it wouldn't become too big or too small,
力を込めたんだ
we put our strength into it.
この蒼くて広い世界に
In this blue, vast world,
無数に散らばった中から
from among countless scattered threads,
別々に二人選んだ糸を
the threads that the two of us chose separately,
お互いたぐり寄せ合ったんだ
we pulled them together towards each other.
結ばれたんじゃなく結んだんだ
It wasn't tied for us; we tied it ourselves.
二人でせーので引っ張ったんだ
The two of us pulled it on three!
大きくも小さくもなりすぎないように
So it wouldn't become too big or too small,
力を込めたんだ
we put our strength into it.
花になって
[Song: Become a Flower]
陰にそっと隠れようが 良いんじゃない？
What's wrong with hiding quietly in the shadows?
蕾のような花だって 有るんじゃない？
Aren't there flowers that look like buds, too?
秘密にして守るのが 良いんじゃない？
Isn't it fine to keep it a secret and protect it?
誰にも邪魔されず 華麗に咲いている
Blooming brilliantly without being disturbed by anyone.
甘い苦いにハマらない
Don't fall for the sweet or the bitter.
その判断が下らない
That judgment is so foolish.
気に病んで下を向かないでいて
Don't worry and look down.
愛になりたがらない
Don't try to become love.
無駄に飾らない
Don't decorate yourself in vain.
綺麗にされた花瓶も
Even a beautifully arranged vase,
肥やしも何もいらない
and fertilizer—we don't need any of it.
その姿が美しい
That figure itself is beautiful.
花になって
Become a flower!
ほら、惨めに笑って、その顔に
Look, laugh miserably with that face.
ゾクゾクして目が離せない
It makes me shiver, I can't take my eyes off you.
味見して
Take a taste.
君の毒は私の薬って
Saying, "Your poison is my medicine."
包んであげる
I will wrap it up for you.
...去って 笑って
...leave it and laugh.
淡い 淡い その笑顔に
To that pale, pale smile,
淡い 淡いって言えば
if I say it's pale, pale,
笑ってくれるかな
will you smile for me?
陰から支えるくらいはいいんじゃない？
Isn't it fine to support you from the shadows?
欲を言えばこの手で
If I had to ask for more, with these hands...
咲かせてみせたい
...I want to make it bloom.
病のように
Like an illness,
心は
my heart
喰らう花
is a flower that consumes,
枯らしたくないのさ
I don't want it to wither.
光が
Even if light
届かずとも
doesn't reach me,
水を注ぎ
I'll keep giving
続けるから
it water.
いい加減に気付いて
Wake up to it already,
君は素敵って
you are wonderful,
うぬぼれてもっとお大事に
be conceited and take better care of yourself.
無自覚なまま
Unconsciously,
愛を蓄えて
accumulating love.
綺麗にされた花瓶も
Even the cleaned-up vase,
肥やしも何もいらない
and fertilizer—nothing is needed.
その姿で咲き誇れ
Bloom in full glory just as you are!
花になって
Become a flower!
ほらニヒルに笑って
Look, smile cynically,
その顔に
on that face,
ドライフラワーみたいな
Like a dried flower,
時間が経てば
as time passes,
きっと きっと きっと きっと
surely, surely, surely, surely,
色褪せる
it will fade away.
月灯りに波紋が揺れる
Ripples sway in the moonlight.
きっと私もどうかしている
Surely I must be losing my mind.
暗闇に色彩が浮かぶ
Colors float in the darkness.
赤、黄色、青が胸の奥
Red, yellow, and blue, deep in my heart.
ずっとあなたの名前を呼ぶ
I keep calling out your name.
好きという気持ちまた変わる
The feeling of love changes again.
声も 顔も
Your voice, your face,
不器用なとこも
even your clumsy side,
全部 全部
everything, everything,
大嫌いだよ
I hate it so much.
まだ枯れない花を
A flower that hasn't withered yet,
君に添えてさ
I'll place it by your side,
ずっと ずっと ずっと ずっと
always, always, always, always,
抱えてよ保存
please hold on to it.
二人三脚 feat. 描汰つな
[Song: Two-Legged Race feat. Nekota Tsuna]
大丈夫と
Saying "I'm okay,"
また嘘をついた
I lied again.
無理してるの
You're pushing yourself,
声でわかるよ
I can tell by your voice,
笑ってるんだよ
even though you're smiling.
二人三脚
[Two-Legged Race]
見た目だとか
Whether it's our looks,
性格だって
or even our personalities,
違うあなた
you are different.
だけど似てる
But we're similar,
どこか痛いとあって
because we both hurt somewhere.
共鳴
Resonance,
すぐにしたんだ
it happened instantly,
惹かれ
we were drawn
あった私たち
to each other.
不思議なこの絆
This mysterious bond.
なんだかさ、寝れなくて
Somehow, I can't sleep.
付き合うよ
I'll keep you company.
夜が明けるまで語り明かそう
Let's talk until the dawn,
朝まで
until morning.
私がね、頑張れる理由
The reason why I can keep trying,
そう、一人じゃないから
is because, yes, I'm not alone!
あなたが笑えば
If you laugh,
私もつられる
I'll also catch it.
隣り合わせの心
Our side-by-side hearts
連鎖してるよ
are linked together.
時には歩幅が
Sometimes our strides
ずれてしまうけど
get out of sync, but
二人
the two of us
呼吸揃えさあ
will align our breathing, and now
未来へと
toward the future,
進んでいこう
let's move forward.
どれくらいの順位かな
I wonder what our rank is,
周りと比べて
compared to those around us.
果てしないトラックを
Running along the endless track,
追いかけるの
chasing after it.
なんて弱気な日も
Even on days when I felt so weak,
激励し続けてくれた
you kept encouraging me.
あなたにいつも感謝
I'm always grateful to you.
転んでも立ち上がる
Even if we fall down, we'll stand up again.
いつだって
Always.
夢を叶えたいんだ
I want to make our dreams come true.
叶えるよ保存
We will.
どんなにね、打ちのめされても
No matter how beaten down we get,
そう、仲間がいるから
yes, because we have our friends!
あなたの悩みは
With your worries,
私が寄り添う
I'll stay by your side.
心が疲れたなら保存
If your heart gets tired,
休憩しよう
let's take a break.
遠慮はしないで
Don't hesitate.
そんなに楽じゃないね
It's not that easy, is it?
二人
The two of us,
肩を組んで
look, with our arms around each other's shoulders,
ほら 何度でも乗り越えよう
will overcome it, no matter how many times.
ほら何度でも乗り越えるよ
See, we'll overcome it again and again.
世界中が敵になっても
Even if the whole world becomes our enemy,
変わらず あなたの味方
I'll always be on your side.
右と左
Right and left,
「友達の証だよ」って
"it's proof of our friendship," we said,
強く、固く、キツく、縛ったリボン
and tied a ribbon strong, tight, and firm.
話題のドラマも
The drama we talked about,
虹の出る空も
and the sky with a rainbow,
掴み取る栄光も
even the glory we'll grasp,
一緒に見たい
I want to see them all with you.
あなたが笑えば
If you laugh, I will too,
私もつられる
I can't help but join in.
隣り合わせの心
Our side-by-side hearts
連鎖してるよ保存
are linked in a chain.
いずれそれぞれの道を歩いても
Even if we walk separate paths someday,
共に支えあおう保存
let's support each other.
さあ未来へと進んで行こう
Come, let's step forward into the future.
どこにいても二人三脚
Wherever we are, we'll run a three-legged race.
huh...
with you...
できたー！
We did it!
二度目だけど
Even though it's our second time,
めっちゃ、私忘れてたから
I totally forgot it, so...
いえいえ
No, no.
6周年！
6th anniversary!
6！
6!
え、そっちで？
Wait, with that hand?
こっちじゃない？
Isn't it this one?
あ、こう？
Ah, like this?
こう？
Like this?
韓国はこうだよ
In Korea, it's like this.
これ勉強になりました、ありがとうございます
I learned something new. Thank you!
6がこうなのね
So 6 is like that.
おめでとう！
Congratulations!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you so much!
ありがとう、嬉しい！
Thank you, I'm so happy!
そうなんですよ、実はこの前、つなのね
That's right, actually, previously, for Tsuna's...
はい
Yes.
来年、ライブ...
Next year... Live...
誕生日ね、はい
My birthday, right? Yes.
そう、誕生日記念のライブに出させていただいたので
Right, since I got to appear in her birthday anniversary live...
今回は、なんかさ、初めてなんだよね
This time, it's actually our first time...
そう！ホロライブのスタジオに来ましたー！
Yes! I came to the Hololive studio!
めちゃくちゃ、いえーい！
Awesome! Yeay!
すごい！すごい！
Amazing! Amazing!
いえーい！ありがとう、わざわざ来てくれて。そうなんだよね
Yeay! Thank you for coming all this way. Yes, indeed.
いっぱい吸っていきます
I'm going to take in as much as I can.
初めて、そう、ホロライブのスタジオで3Dでコラボしました。ありがとう！
Our first time, yes, doing a 3D collab in the Hololive studio. Thank you!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you very much!
そしてなんと、2年ぶりですよ
And believe it or not, it's been two years.
そうなんだよね
That's true.
そう、この「二人三脚」という曲をやらせていただいたんですけど
Yes, we got to perform this song, 'Ninin Sankyaku'...
トワのファーストソロライブの時に
Back during Towa's first solo live,
初めてやって、覚えてた？振り
we did it for the first time. Did you remember the choreo?
いや、もう、完全に忘れてた
No, I had completely forgotten it.
でもわかる、色んなのやっていくとさ、忘れちゃうから、しかも2年ぶりだし
But I get it. When you do so many things, you forget them. Plus, it's been two years.
そう、忘れてちゃったけど、でも前はさ、シークレットゲストだったじゃん
Yeah, I forgot it, but last time, I was a secret guest.
でも初、なんかこう、サムネに私がいる！
But for the first time, I'm right there in the thumbnail!
そう、いるー！ってなって
Yeah, like, 'I'm here!'
嬉しい。Demo hontou ni ne, ano kyoku
I'm glad. But really, that song...
あそこで終わりじゃなくて、こうやってね、またできたのがすごい嬉しいので
Instead of it ending there, I'm so happy we could do it again like this.
ありがとうございました、ということで
So, thank you so much.
ありがとうございました
Thank you very much.
はい
Yes.
ということで、なんかソロライブの時にコラボしたあと、こうやって3Dでコラボすることなかったから
And since we hadn't collabed in 3D like this since that solo live,
今日は、みなさん、無料で今お届けしているので
today, we are bringing this to everyone for free...
無料です！
It's free!
はい
Yes.
えっと、じゃあ、写真タイムするか
Well, then, should we do some photo time?
え、する！
Oh, let's do it!
改めて
Once again.
え、どう、どういうポーズが良いですか？
What kind of pose should we do?
え、指を動かして...
Um, moving our fingers...
指を動かして？
Moving our fingers?
ダサい、動き！
That movement looks so uncool!
何これ？
What is this?
陰キャピース
The introvert peace sign.
それ可愛い、可愛くピースやってみてよ
That's cute. Try doing a cute peace sign.
可愛い？
Cute?
え、何が可愛いの？これ古い？
Wait, what's cute? Is this outdated?
古いって言われない？大丈夫？
They won't say it's outdated, right? Is it okay?
今の流行りは？
What's trendy now?
今の流行り何？これ？これ？
What is trendy now? This? This?
え、違う...
Wait, no...
同じやつやってる
We're doing the same one.
同じやつ
The same one.
可愛い！
So cute!
私もやりたいです
I want to do it too.
おおお、すごい、すごい！
Ooh, awesome, awesome!
ダサい
So uncool.
喜びのダンス
The dance of joy.
あ、出た
Ah, there it is.
これできる？
Can you do this?
アイドル
Idol.
アイドルね
Idol style.
アイドル
Idol.
いえーい！
Yeay!
ありがとうございます
Thank you very much.
いっぱい撮ってね
Take lots of photos!
いっぱい撮ってね、ありがとう
Take lots of photos! Thank you.
え、どう？
Wait, how about this?
なんだよ、おい
Hey, what is that?
ハート作るからさ、グーして
I'm going to make a heart, so make a fist.
トワがグーの方？グーして
I should do the fist? Making a fist...
こう
Like this.
ありがとうございます！
Thank you so much!
漫画？
Is this from a manga?
嬉しい、可愛い、ステージも
I'm happy. It's cute, and the stage too!
かっこいい！
Cool!
つなちゃんも可愛いじゃないですか！
Tsuna-chan, you're cute too!
えー、嬉しいです。
Aw, I'm so happy.
なんかすごい、はだけちゃってごめんなさいね。
I'm sorry my outfit is so exposed, haha.
トワちゃんにはないものを持ってる気がして、すごい。
I feel like you have something Towa-chan doesn't have, it's amazing.
やめてください。
Please stop!
いや、でも別に、何とは言ってないんですけど。
No, but I didn't specify what it was!
あ、そうですね。あっ、そうそうそうです。
Ah, that's right. Yes, indeed.
ということでね、今日は本当に来てくれてありがとうございました。
Anyway, thank you so much for coming today.
こちらこそ、ありがとう。
The pleasure is mine, thank you.
またね、コラボもしましょう！
Let's collab again sometime!
しよう！遊ぼう！
Let's! Let's hang out!
遊ぼう！ということで、以上、つなトワでしたー！
Let's hang out! So, that was TsunaTowa!
バイバイー！
Bye-bye!
頑張って！
Do your best!
ありがとうー！
Thank you!
第ゼロ感
[Song: Dai Zero Kan]
群れを逸れて 夢を咥えた...
Straying from the herd, biting into a dream...
それが最後になる気がしたんだ
...I felt like it would be the last time.
獣は砂を一握り撒いた...
The beast scattered a handful of sand...
それが最後になる気がしたんだ
...I felt like it would be the last time.
不確かな夢叶えるのさ 約束の夜に
I'll make my uncertain dream come true on the promised night.
微かな風に願うのさ 静寂の朝に
I'll make a wish on a faint breeze in the quiet morning.
遠い星の少年は その腕に約束の飾り
The boy from a distant star has a promised ornament on his arm.
まだ旅路の最中さ 幻惑の園に
Still in the middle of a journey in the garden of illusion.
霞んで消えた 轍の先へ...
Beyond the faded and vanished ruts...
それが最後になる気がしたんだ
...I felt like it would be the last time.
古い夢を紡ぎ直せば...
If we re-spin our old dreams...
それが最後になる気がしたんだ
...I felt like it would be the last time.
熱砂を蹴り抗うのさ 約束の前に
Kicking the hot sand, we'll resist before the promise.
命綱は無いのさ サーカスの夜に
There's no safety net on this circus night.
まだ旅路の最中さ あの場所に加速するさらに
Still in the middle of our journey, accelerating even more toward that place.
雨上がりのシャンデリア 幻惑の園に
A chandelier after the rain, in the garden of illusion.
Swish da chakku yo
Ma source, my sweetie trip, back of kiddie, mean now
Go, youngster, sissy, sir
Go, youngster, sissy, pass
Go, youngster, sissy, sir, and pass
Swish da chakku yo
Fast corner, penetrate, a past-pass, speedball
Get, triple, buzzer-beater
What about some sweetie-pop, kiddie-chan?
Fast corner, get up, beat!
Fast corner, penetrate, a past-pass, speedball
What about some sweetie-pop, kiddie-chan?
Just what about some sweetie-pop, kiddie-chan?
More than thirty years, expectation!
Cool Southern, e-habby
永遠の意味
To you, who doesn't know
知らぬ君に
the meaning of eternity,
答えを示す時だ
it is time to show you the answer.
夢幻に続く螺旋の先へ
Beyond the spiral leading to the infinite fantasy.
夢幻
作詞・作曲: MY FIRST STORY / CHIMERAZ
Mugen
Lyrics & Composition: MY FIRST STORY / CHIMERAZ
言い訳に聞こえた理由は
The reason it sounded like an excuse
儚い未来手繰った弱さ
is the weakness of chasing a fleeting future,
それを強さとはき違えている
mistaking that for strength.
憎い 憎い
I hate it, I hate it,
醜い 醜い
it's ugly, it's ugly,
月を隠すほどの
enough to hide the moon.
黒く 黒く
Black, black,
淀む 心
stagnant heart...
君さえ居なければ
If only you weren't here.
ゆらいでる
Swaying,
swaying,
花のように意思を繋ぐ
connecting our wills like a flower.
奪っていく
Stealing away,
stealing away,
嵐のように心を裂く
tearing the heart apart like a storm.
永遠の意味
To you, who doesn't know
知らぬ君に
the meaning of eternity,
答えを示す時だ
it is time to show you the answer.
夢幻に続く螺旋の先に
At the end of the spiral leading to the infinite fantasy,
待つのは誰
who is it that waits?
生まれ落ちた運命を飲んだ
I swallowed the fate I was born with,
背負った数の名前を覚えた
I remembered the names I carried on my back,
爛れるほど 心燃やす感情
an emotion that burns my heart until it festers.
憎い 憎い
I hate it, I hate it,
醜い 醜い
it's ugly, it's ugly,
世界を分かつほどの
enough to divide the world.
怒り 怒り
Anger, anger,
燃やす 心
burning heart...
君さえ居なければ
If only you weren't here.
ゆらいでる
Swaying,
swaying,
花のように意思を繋ぐ
connecting our wills like a flower.
奪っていく
Stealing away,
stealing away,
嵐のように心を裂く
tearing the heart apart like a storm.
永遠の意味
To you, who doesn't know
知らぬ君に
the meaning of eternity,
答えを示す時だ
it is time to show you the answer.
夢幻に続く螺旋の先で
Beyond the spiral leading to the infinite fantasy,
待つのは誰
who is it that waits?
鬼哭に耳を傾けた仕舞よ
Listening to the wailing of spirits, it is the end,
身に宿る万物で終いよ
with all creation dwelling in this body, it is over.
夢幻を他者に託した弱き人
The weak who entrusted their dreams to others.
命の輝きは幾星霜に
The radiance of life over countless years,
祈りの瞬きが照らす斜陽に
to the setting sun illuminated by the flicker of prayer,
千夜を身に宿し
harboring a thousand nights within,
解を押し付ける
forcing the answer upon you.
枯らしていく
Withering away,
withering away,
夢幻の夜に花を裂く
tearing flowers apart in the night of fantasy.
繋いでいく
Connecting,
connecting,
嵐に種を撒いていく
sowing seeds in the storm.
ゆらいでる
Swaying,
swaying,
花のように意思を繋ぐ
connecting our wills like a flower.
奪っていく
Stealing away,
stealing away,
嵐のように心を裂く
tearing the heart apart like a storm.
永遠の意味
To you, who doesn't know
知らぬ君に
the meaning of eternity,
答えを示す時だ
it is time to show you the answer.
夢幻に続く螺旋の先で
Beyond the spiral leading to the infinite fantasy,
待つのは誰
who is it that waits?
以上、ゲストパートでした！
That's all for the guest part!
ゲストパートでした！イェーイ！
That was the guest part! Yay!
はい！ということでね、たくさんのメンバーがね、お祝いしにきてくれました！やったー！
Yes! And so, many members came to celebrate! Yay!
そして、本日の6周年...
And today, for my 6th anniversary...
ライブなんですけれども
For this live performance,
ロックフェスみたいのをちょっとイメージしておりまして
we went for something like a rock festival style,
ちょっとね、えー、ダンスよりも、あの、好きに動いてねのフリーの動きを多めにしてみたので
and instead of dancing, we included more free-style movements where we can move as we please.
えー、それぞれのゲストと、とわちゃんのね、えー、個性がでてるパフォーマンスになってるんじゃないかなと思います！
So I think it shows the unique personalities of each guest and myself!
なので、配信とかを見直して、え、ここ癖でてるなー、とか思いながらもう一回改めて見ていただけると嬉しいです！
Because of that, I'd be glad if you rewatch the archive and find those personal quirks!
そして！まだ、この後も歌いますから！チャンネルはそのままで！
And! I still have songs to sing, so keep your channel right here!
ういーー
Wheee!
で、プチ告知させてもらいます！
Now, let me make a quick announcement!
はい！えー、セカンドソロライブで発表いたしました！
Yes! As announced during my 2nd Solo Live...
『勇者パーティーを追い出された器用貧乏』というアニメの主題歌
The anime theme song for "Yusha Party wo Oidasareta Kiyobinbou"...
「シルベ」のMVが、この後、配信が終わり次第、常闇トワチャンネルにて上がります！
"Shirube"'s MV will be uploaded to the Tokoyami Towa Channel right after this stream!
めちゃくちゃいいMVになったので、ぜひぜひ見てください！
It turned out to be an incredible MV, so please watch it!
見ないと人生を損した...とまではいかないかもしれないけど、損するかもしれないくらいです！
If you don't watch it, well, maybe not to the extent of ruining your life, but you'll definitely be missing out!
はい、気合いを入れて作ってもらいました！
Yes, they put so much energy into making it!
はい、よろしくお願いいたします！そしてアニメはなんと明日から放送開始！楽しみ！ぜひ見てね！
Thank you very much! And the anime actually starts airing tomorrow! I'm excited! Please check it out!
そして、MVだけではありません！ありません！
And that's not all! That's not all!
「シルベ」のなんと、シングルCDが発売決定！本日から予約できます！
A single CD for "Shirube" is officially releasing! You can pre-order starting today!
なんですが、こちらのね、詳細は配信の最後にまとめてお伝えするので、ここもチャンネルはそのままに！
But I'll share the details of that at the end of the stream, so don't switch channels!
そしてさらに！本日はね、周年記念なので、グッズのお知らせもあります！もちろん！
And what's more! Since today is the anniversary, we have merchandise announcements! Of course!
はい、こちらも詳細も、えー、後でまたお伝えしますので、チャンネルはそのままに！今日のキーワードは「チャンネルはそのままに」
Yes, details for that will also be shared later, so keep your channel right here! Today's keyword is "don't switch channels"!
え、そしてね、えー、メンバー限定のミニライブも今日はありますので、ぜひメンバーシップに入っていただけたら嬉しくって、チャンネルはそのままに！
And we also have a members-only mini-live today, so I'd love for you to join the membership. Keep your channel right here!
あははは。どんだけ言うんだよって！
Ahaha, "How many times are you gonna say that?!" right?
はい、ということでありがとうございました。はい、じゃあ最後にね、1曲歌ってから告知しようかなと思うので、聴いてください！
Right, so thank you very much. I'll sing one last song before the final announcement, so please listen!
最後の1曲、「シルベ」
The last song: "Shirube".
Warning! Warning! 隣り合わせで
Warning! Warning! Side by side,
May God bless you 言葉のあやね
May God bless you, a figure of speech...
Warning! Warning! 彷徨いながら
I will stay true to myself 'cause of you
Warning! Warning! While wandering,
I will stay true to myself 'cause of you.
シルベ
作詞・作曲・編曲：古閑理平 (YOURNESS)
[Shirube
Lyrics, Composition & Arrangement: Rihei Koga (YOURNESS)]
はじめから みたいに
As if from the very beginning,
何もない世界に
in a world with nothing,
理不尽に囚われる
unjustly imprisoned,
黙って しまうほどの 恐怖はない
there is no fear great enough to silence me.
使い捨てみたいに
To you who let go of my hand
手を離したあなたに
as if I were disposable,
昨日とは まるで違う
completely different from yesterday,
わかったところで しょうもない
even if I understand it, it's useless.
変わっていく身体と
My changing body and
心の中で 響く VOICE
the VOICE echoing in my heart,
間違ってなかったと
believing I wasn't wrong,
ただ この空を 眺めてる
I am just staring at this sky.
I still 重なってくたび
I still remember every time
思い出して しまうのに
our paths cross, even though...
誤魔化して しまうのは
the reason I hide my feelings
確かにあった 後悔から
is because of a regret that certainly existed.
誓ったはずなんだ さよならすらシルベにしよう
I swore to make even our farewells a guidepost,
光に触れるたび 願ってしまうように
so that I end up wishing every time I touch the light.
And still I rise!!
染まっていく 必要もない
There's no need to be dyed.
越えられない border
An impassable border,
揺れる意志を convert
convert the wavering will,
嘘で染めるような日々じゃ
In days stained with lies,
振り返った時には heartache
when looking back, there is heartache.
また夜が明ける wake up
Night breaks again, wake up,
夢の中の flavor
the flavor inside the dream,
誰もいなくなった道を歩いている
walking down a path where everyone is gone.
今の私に
Onto my current self,
迷いすら重ねてく
I pile even doubts,
月明かりの夜は
On a moonlit night...
さよならすらシルベにしよう
Let's make even our goodbyes a guidepost
光を繋ぐたび
Every time we connect the lights
浮かぶ星座のように
Like a floating constellation
選んできた道のりを今も
The path I have chosen even now,
いずれ後悔してしまう時が来ても
Even if the time comes when I will eventually regret it...
私はまだ止まらない
I still won't stop
夜空に浮かぶ月の光を
The moonlight floating in the night sky...
見上げた空に散らばる星の宝石を
The star jewels scattered in the sky I looked up at...
道標にして
Making them my guidepost,
帰る場所
A place to return to
I still 重ねてくたび
I still, every time it piles up...
はい、着やすいね、サイズにさせていただいております。
Yes, we've made it into an easy-to-wear size!
よかったー！
I'm so glad!
ちゃんと裏地もね、えー、ネオンピンクみたいな形の、ネオンピンク、形じゃないね、ネオンピンクの色になってますから、
The lining is also neon pink—well, not neon pink shape, but neon pink color—
本当にトワ様になっちゃったみたいなジャージになってます。
It's a jersey that makes you feel like you've really become Towa-sama!
ちょっと大きめのサイズなんで、あの、みんな着やすいのかなと思います。
It's a bit of a larger size, so I think it'll be easy for everyone to wear.
はい、ということで、じゃあ最後3つ目。
Alright, with that, let's move on to the third and final item.
ビビハンドストラップ！
The Bibi Hand Strap!
やっぱね、あの、結構あの、トワのジャージとかは、結構あの、ザ・グッズ、グッズというかさ、キャラグッズみたいな感じするんですけど、
You know, things like Towa's jersey feel very much like classic merchandise, or character goods, but...
通常使いもね、しやすいような、えー、使い勝手の良いようなグッズも欲しいなと思いまして、ハンドストラップを作ってみました！
I also wanted some merchandise that would be easy to use in daily life, so I tried making a hand strap!
イェーイ！
Yay!
えー、カラーリングもね、すごい落ち着いていて、トワっぽい色になったんじゃないかなと思うので、ぜひご購入お願いいたします。
The coloring is also very subtle, and I think it turned out to be a very Towa-like color, so please consider buying it!
えー、こちら、えー、スマートフォンの画像はついておりますが、スマートフォンはついてきませんから、
And while there is an image of a smartphone here, it does not come with a smartphone,
よろしくお願いいたします！
so please keep that in mind!
はい、で、こちらのね、セット、えー、ご購入してくださった方には、
And for those who purchase this set...
えー、笑顔のトワの、えー、箔押し複製サイン入りチェキ風ブロマイドカードがついてきます！
a Cheki-style bromide card with a smiling Towa and a foil-stamped replica signature will be included!
はい。で、そしてね、数量限定で直筆サイン入り、こっちは直筆サインで、えー、お渡ししたいなと思っておりますので、ぜひ、どっちも手に入れてくれればなと思います。
Also, in limited quantities, there's a hand-signed version! I'd love to deliver that to you, so I hope you can get your hands on both!
かわいい！よろしくお願いいたします！
So cute! Please look forward to it!
ということで、えー、以上こんな感じで、常闇トワ6周年記念のグッズの紹介でしたー！
And with that, that's all for the introduction of Tokoyami Towa's 6th-anniversary merchandise!
シルベットとね、常闇トワのグッズ、両方よろしくお願いいたします！
Please check out both Sylvet and Tokoyami Towa's merchandise!
ということで、今日は見てくれてありがとう！
So, thank you for watching today!
この後はメン限で、ライブしますから、ぜひよろしくお願いいたします！
After this, I'll be doing a members-only live stream, so please join us!
イェーイ！
Yay!
じゃあね、メンバーシップ加入と、えー、グッズ購入と、全部よろしくね！
Well then, please join the membership, buy the merch, and check out everything!
あけおめ！バイバイ！
Happy New Year! Bye-bye!